we're gonna practice the same meditation
as yesterday did if you didn't record it
you're welcome to record it okay which
is some mixture three things what don't
man
exchanging self and others and the seven
steps Mummy Mummy manatee
okay here we go everybody seven
then we'll start with a small
preparation relax your mouth pull in
your stomach small smile eyelids are
relaxed fingers are relaxed shoulders go
back a little bit
and then we'll come to our breath long
exhales and put your mind on your breath
in the same way that you put your head
on your pillow and just relax into the
breath
then please and invite one of your
teachers in your life maybe your mom
maybe you're done or some other teacher
to come and sit with you in the
meditation and give you their blessing
didn't think of something you love about
this person and this is like a bowing
down to them just to recognize the
beauty in them and something you admire
please don't make any noise we should be
sitting still
then think of something you didn't last
day or two which was not very nice maybe
you were irritated at someone else here
that you teacher no clean it
then let your teacher know about
something really nice you've done I
think coming here to Diamond Mountain
it's so difficult to get here and you
worked so hard to come here and tell
your teacher about it they're very happy
maybe one of the most important things
in your learn it will help your next
life also
then ask your teachers to keep teaching
could be anyone around you anyone around
us can give us inspiration can teach us
people who give us trouble can also
teach us we become stronger better
people learning to be patient with them
then ask our teacher to stay in our life
please don't ever leave me I couldn't
live that life without my teacher
then we'll start the meditation it'll be
a Tumlin meditation and we're so close
to ourselves we we take care of
ourselves before anything else and
there's a tomlin meditation for that
take care of my afternoon cell stand
help to myself this afternoon and we've
done that that's a good meditation you
can do it and we've done Tumlin
meditations for people we care about our
loved ones
family members who might be sick or have
passed away or and now we're gonna do
meditation which begins with equanimity
it means let's try to think of someone
who's not very close to us someone who's
not family member could be someone we
don't really think about much it could
even be someone we're having a little
bit of trouble with them and let's be
give equal time to tomlin for people we
don't know so well or people even that
we have a little bit of trouble with
them so please think of someone not your
usual close friend or a family member or
but rather someone that you wouldn't
normally prayer prayer pray for someone
not so close and let's give people equal
time too
one who's not so close but who needs
some help today equanimity
every being around us has been our mom
before in the past life there's no
beginning to our mind if one moment of
mine the present moment of mine right
now flowed from the mind of an hour ago
and if only mine can create mine then it
proves we have no beginning our life has
no beginning our mind has no beginning
and that mind has created many mothers
we have been the child of every being we
ever met every bird every small animal
here at Diamond Mountain every person in
the airport every person we've ever met
they have been our mom so let's think
about this how this person has been my
mom this person I'm meditating about
today must have been my mom many times
then think about all the nice things
they did for us when they were our mom
there's a step number three first was
equanimity choosing a person that we
won't usually choose second was seeing
that they have been my mom and then
thirdly let's think about all the things
they did for us when they were our mom
they went through tremendous pain to
give us birth and then the long pain of
many years of taking care of us worrying
about us how to feed us how to give us
clothing how to protect us how to
educate us all the countless trouble and
pressure on your mom pressure never lets
up for the first 20 years they have to
take care of you it's their
responsibility and this person did it
for me
I just forgot about it
then I should do something to pay her
back I shouldn't just forget her that's
the step number four let me pay her back
it's a good thing to do it's right
let me do my best to make her happy in
this life
then how much effort should I put into
paying her back how much time do I have
to pay her back today for example whose
happiness is more important whose
happiness should get more hours of my
time or more minutes of my time should I
give her one hour or should I give her
two hours and give myself five hours six
hours up how much is she worth how much
am i worth why should I give myself more
time than I get to her isn't her
happiness as important to her as my
happiness is important to me why should
I give myself more time attention and
care then I give to her shouldn't it be
equal don't we both want happiness the
same shouldn't I work for other people
as much as I work for myself this is
step 5 it's called equal rights other
people and myself we have equal right to
my time
you
then step number six is thinking about
where things really come from I things
come to me even the time in my life that
I have to take care of myself even those
hours has come from taking care of
others in the past so if I just focus on
myself on what I want and I don't give
any time to this person my my mom then
actually my life will be more unhappy so
if I don't give her my time and I don't
give her my attention in the future my
life will be even worse I'm hurting
myself if I don't give equal time to
other people in myself I'm only hurting
myself I won't be happy I don't get what
I want if I only focus on my son
step 7 if I really want more happiness
in my own life if I want to be happy
then I don't really have a choice I have
to get this person my attention in my
time it's the only way I will have a
good life that's the only way I will be
happy it seems like if I give them more
time and more attention then I'm taking
time away from myself but my time comes
from giving my time to other people so
the smartest thing if I want to be happy
I want to have time and I want love of
other people I don't have a choice I I
have to give my time to this person even
though they're not my favorite person
they're not my family or close friend
but if I want more time and I want more
love in my life I don't have a choice I
have to take care of them I have to give
them my time
in step number eight this is really how
I can be happy for my whole life and
this is like Tao this is like the way of
things
this is creation this is what made the
world is how much I give to other people
so it's a right right thing to do and it
feels good for the first time in my life
I can feel like I'm doing the right
thing if I take care of this other
people and I give them my time happily
with understanding then some part of me
understands that some part of me knows
it's the right thing to do and I feel
relaxed and I feel finally I'm doing the
right thing this struggle to take care
of myself the struggle to spend the
hours on myself and pretending it's okay
to ignore other people it's it feels
wrong to me and if I relax and give my
time to other people give my attention
to other people finally it feels
comfortable and it makes sense and I'm
doing the right thing so this number a
is just enjoy how good it feels to do
the right thing and stop struggling
against doing the right thing give your
time to other people
and this is real happiness
you
now step 9 6 changing myself and this
other person so I put my mind in their
body their eyes may be closed then they
open their eyes and they look at me how
how does it feel to look at Michael when
people look at Michael how does it feel
when this person who I are not that
close to them I don't take care of them
usually but when they look at me and
Michael how do they feel they know I I
don't care about them that much they
know I don't want to give them my time
but how does it feel to them to look at
Michael and and know that Michael
doesn't really care so much about them
how lonely it feels and how sad it feels
to them that someone doesn't really care
about them so put yourself in their mind
and look at you
and see how it feels to be with you and
to be ignored by you
then let's look at those feelings in
their heart it's like a black cloud this
is step number 10 of the 13 steps and
all that feeling of being ignored by my
color not being loved by Michael feeling
that Michael doesn't want to give me his
time all those sad feelings that they
have now we understand how they feel we
can see the dark smoke in their heart
this sad feeling about Michael so let's
decide to take it out of them and we're
going to use both nostrils first we look
at this beautiful Lotus in our heart
beautiful pink Lotus make it super
beautiful get the color very beautiful
the Lotus is very delicate
it's very wine it looks very beautiful
inside your heart it has a very subtle
and fragrant smell very attractive spend
some time make the Lotus beautiful
in the middle of the lorises this
beautiful diamond I like to use the
diamond ring meditation ring with the
raw diamond big piece of raw diamond
sparkling and pure these are the two
valuable things I have in my heart these
are the two most precious things I own
in my life
is not money it's not houses it's not
even my body it's my love which is the
lordís and my understanding of where
things are coming from the pen which is
the diamond these are the two most
precious things I have these two things
I can take with me after I die these are
things that I really own and they are
the basis of all the happiness
then we will take in breath slowly we
will pump the black smoke out of our
friend and bring it to the front of your
nose and then together we'll breathe it
in okay so take a few breaths pump the
darkness out of there heart up here
throw up their throat out of their nose
and it drifts over to me and bravely I
will decide to take it in on the count
of three I will breathe in this
blackness immediately it will go to the
diamond in the heart and there'll be a
bright flash of light like lightning and
all that sadness that they have will be
destroyed all their sadness about
knowing that I don't really want to give
them my time will be destroyed on the
count of three one two and three the
black smoke comes to the diamond they
touch there is a flash like lightning
and then all that sadness is gone
disappears in a gray smoke and then the
smoke disappears and there's a sense of
relief from the other person they don't
have this darkness anymore they don't
know what happened they don't know you
did anything but wherever they are right
now
they feel a sense of relief and some
kind of comfort
then let's give them our happiness let's
give them our time let's give them our
attention and I take some deep breaths
out golden light I like to add the smell
of the Lotus and the beauty is leaving
from my heart out my nostrils and coming
to their heart
coming down their throat
your time you're not in any rush we're
meditating right now the world can wait
all the things we have to do can wait
don't let subtle busy mine knock on the
door of your meditation this is my time
this is my meditation time the things I
have to do today can never wait until my
meditation is done
then by doing this meditation I become a
different kind of person slowly every
day if I do this meditation my
personality will change I will become a
more loving person I'll become some kind
of very unusual person who enjoys giving
their time to others and never complains
happy to sacrifice their own desires to
help other people and quietly I will
become a different kind of person and
people around me will sense it they will
feel how happy I am to give my time to
others how much joy I take in my life
how how much happier I have become since
I started doing this meditation then I
become like a virus like a meditation
virus like a virus of caring for others
and when we're selfish when we don't
want to give our time to others and we
don't want to give them our attention
when we're selfish that selfishness
tends to spread around us people feel
our hesitation to share our time in our
love and then they become more selfish
but we become a bad example and like
cancer it starts to spread to our
friends and other people we mean so
today because I'm doing this meditation
and I'm taking pleasure in giving my
time and my love to someone I don't
really know that well or maybe I don't
really care about them I don't like them
this example new way to become happy hmm
it will start to spread people will
sense it people around me will be
affected by it they will be changed I
will become a virus and this is meaning
of body supper this is what a body
suffers a virus of a new way to be to
treat people so the final step is to
enjoy being a bodhisattva virus some
kind of light for other people good
example so I enjoy being a good example
a light for others then you can open
your eyes take a stitch